<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>thoughts on circuitshelter</title><link>https://circuitshelter.com/tags/thoughts/</link><description>Recent content in thoughts on circuitshelter</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 16:29:47 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://circuitshelter.com/tags/thoughts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>On Coding for Fun</title><link>https://circuitshelter.com/posts/on-coding-for-fun/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 16:29:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://circuitshelter.com/posts/on-coding-for-fun/</guid><description>Software is not always a tool or a solution. And it doesn’t always need to serve a high purpose or solve problems.
Coding is a very accessible form of expression that can be applied to virtually anything including things not related to your job or interests. You can code things for fun and feel good about it as much as when you do it for profit. And you really can’t put a price tag on feeling good.</description><content>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Software is not always a tool or a solution.&lt;/strong>
And it doesn’t always need to serve a high purpose or solve problems.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Coding is a very accessible form of expression that can be applied to virtually anything including things not related to your job or interests.
You can code things for fun and feel good about it as much as when you do it for profit.
And you really can’t put a price tag on feeling good.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It can become your personal bonsai tree or zen garden.
This type of activity can be relaxing and even therapeutic since it’s takes place in safe environment where no money and competition involved.
And still this process will challenge you in a ways that are beneficial for your tech and problem solving skills development.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s can someday become a part of something public if you think it can be valuable for others, &lt;strong>but it’s not the main goal.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>It’s just you having a good time in a way you like it, and you doing it just because.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://pixeljoint.com/pixelart/133587.htm">original pixel art on cover&lt;/a>&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>