<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>emulation on circuitshelter</title><link>https://circuitshelter.com/tags/emulation/</link><description>Recent content in emulation on circuitshelter</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 12:12:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://circuitshelter.com/tags/emulation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Where to find old games and software</title><link>https://circuitshelter.com/posts/old-games-and-software/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 12:12:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://circuitshelter.com/posts/old-games-and-software/</guid><description>Safety First! Always be careful when downloading and especially when executing ANYTHING from the internet! It&amp;rsquo;s very hard to check ingenuity of the old or abandoned software. Make sure you doing it in a safe environment like virtual machine or isolated box. Never run anything questionable along side of ANY critical or personal data! Respect the intellectual property rights. The List The Internet Archive Software Collection: largest vintage and historical software library in the world, providing instant access to millions of programs, CD-ROM images, documentation and multimedia.</description><content>&lt;h1 id="safety-first">Safety First!&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Always be careful when downloading and especially when executing ANYTHING from the internet!&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>It&amp;rsquo;s very hard to check ingenuity of the old or abandoned software.&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Make sure you doing it in a safe environment like virtual machine or isolated box.&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Never run anything questionable along side of ANY critical or personal data!&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Respect the intellectual property rights.&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h1 id="the-list">The List&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://archive.org/details/software/">The Internet Archive Software Collection&lt;/a>: largest vintage and historical software library in the world, providing instant access to millions of programs, CD-ROM images, documentation and multimedia. The collection includes a broad range of software related materials including shareware, freeware, video news releases about software titles, speed runs of actual software game play, previews and promos for software games, high-score and skill replays of various game genres, and the art of filmmaking with real-time computer game engines.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.mobygames.com/">MobyGames&lt;/a>: is the oldest, largest and most accurate video game database. Spanning over 260 platforms from 1950 to date. For 20 years, it&amp;rsquo;s been widely considered the IMDB of the games industry and often referenced as the canonical source for game information.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://macintoshgarden.org/">The Macintosh Garden&lt;/a>: is an &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Abandonware">abandonware&lt;/a> archive, dedicated in particular to supporting the Macintosh computer platform. A notable feature of Macintosh Garden is its emphasis on emulation, encouraging users to run historical software on modern systems. Software featured on the Macintosh Garden has been discontinued by their publishers and is no longer commercially available. The Macintosh Garden aims to preserve these treasures for future generations, providing documentation and downloads of the original files.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.tosecdev.org/">TOSEC&lt;/a>: The Old School Emulation Center (TOSEC) is a retrocomputing initiative dedicated to the cataloging and preservation of software, firmware and resources for microcomputers, minicomputers and video game consoles. The main goal of the project is to catalog and audit various kinds of software and firmware images for these systems.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.myabandonware.com/">My Abandonware&lt;/a>: was created in February 2009. Over the years, thousands of games have been added to the site. Authors want to create the best video game museum on the web and let everyone around the world enjoy the incredible amount of great software created in the 80s and 90s. 18k+ games are available at the moment.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://redump.org/">Redump.org&lt;/a>: is an disc preservation database and internet community dedicated to collecting precise and accurate information about every video game ever released on optical media of any system. The goal is to make blueprints of the data on console and PC game discs. Redump also provides guides to ensure the dumps are correctly done. Users of the website who follow the guides correctly are encouraged to share their results to help build the database. Multiple dumps of games with the same serial number by different people are collected to ensure the same results are gathered, which help correct any incorrect dumps in the database as well as to help recognize alternate versions of the same game.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Also take a look at &lt;a href="https://circuitshelter.com/posts/free-and-open-source-game-engines">free and open source game engines&lt;/a> that allows to play old games on modern platforms.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>RetroArch now available on the Amazon App Store</title><link>https://circuitshelter.com/posts/retroarch-amazon-app-store/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 11:47:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://circuitshelter.com/posts/retroarch-amazon-app-store/</guid><description>As of this moment, RetroArch is available on:
Directly (here) Steam (here, available by requesting access) Google Play Store (here and here) Amazon App Store (here) RetroArch is a frontend for emulators, game engines and media players.
It enables you to run classic games on a wide range of computers and consoles through its slick graphical interface. Settings are also unified so configuration is done once and for all.</description><content>&lt;p>As of this moment, RetroArch is available on:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Directly&lt;/strong> (&lt;a href="https://www.retroarch.com/?page=platforms">here&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Steam&lt;/strong> (&lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1118310/RetroArch/">here&lt;/a>, available by requesting access)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Google Play Store&lt;/strong> (&lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.retroarch">here&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.retroarch.aarch64">here&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Amazon App Store&lt;/strong> (&lt;a href="https://amazon.com/dp/B09753XRV">here&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.retroarch.com/">RetroArch&lt;/a> is a frontend for emulators, game engines and media players.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It enables you to run classic games on a wide range of computers and consoles through its slick graphical interface. Settings are also unified so configuration is done once and for all.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In addition to this, you are able to run original game discs (CDs) from RetroArch.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>RetroArch has advanced features like shaders, netplay, rewinding, next-frame response times, runahead, machine translation, blind accessibility features, and more!&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>