<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>games on circuitshelter</title><link>https://circuitshelter.com/categories/games/</link><description>Recent content in games on circuitshelter</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 12:24:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://circuitshelter.com/categories/games/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>3D level design museum</title><link>https://circuitshelter.com/posts/noclip-video-game-museum/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 12:24:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://circuitshelter.com/posts/noclip-video-game-museum/</guid><description>noclip.website: is a celebration of video game level design and art. It&amp;rsquo;s a chance to explore and deepen your appreciation for some of your favorite 3D games.
https://github.com/magcius/noclip.website</description><content>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://noclip.website/">noclip.website&lt;/a>: is a celebration of video game level design and art. It&amp;rsquo;s a chance to explore and deepen your appreciation for some of your favorite 3D games.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/magcius/noclip.website">https://github.com/magcius/noclip.website&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></content></item><item><title>Where to find old games and software</title><link>https://circuitshelter.com/posts/old-games-and-software/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 12:12:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://circuitshelter.com/posts/old-games-and-software/</guid><description>Stores If your title is here, this is the best choice.
GOG: The Good Old Games (GOG) is a digital distribution platform with a curated selection of games, a &amp;ldquo;you buy it, you own it&amp;rdquo; philosophy, and vast selection of classic game titles for Windows, Mac &amp;amp; Linux, DRM-free.
Steam: the biggest video game digital distribution service around.
EBay: here you can find almost anything available on real physical media.</description><content>&lt;h1 id="stores">Stores&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;code>If your title is here, this is the best choice.&lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.gog.com/">GOG&lt;/a>: The Good Old Games (GOG) is a digital distribution platform with a curated selection of games, a &amp;ldquo;you buy it, you own it&amp;rdquo; philosophy, and vast selection of classic game titles for Windows, Mac &amp;amp; Linux, DRM-free.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/">Steam&lt;/a>: the biggest video game digital distribution service around.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.ebay.com/">EBay&lt;/a>: here you can find almost anything available on real physical media.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h1 id="databases">Databases&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.mobygames.com/">MobyGames&lt;/a>: is the oldest, largest and most accurate video game database. Spanning over 260 platforms from 1950 to date. For 20 years, it&amp;rsquo;s been widely considered the IMDB of the games industry and often referenced as the canonical source for game information.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://redump.org/">Redump.org&lt;/a>: is an disc preservation database and internet community dedicated to collecting precise and accurate information about every video game ever released on optical media of any system. The goal is to make blueprints of the data on console and PC game discs. Redump also provides guides to ensure the dumps are correctly done. Users of the website who follow the guides correctly are encouraged to share their results to help build the database. Multiple dumps of games with the same serial number by different people are collected to ensure the same results are gathered, which help correct any incorrect dumps in the database as well as to help recognize alternate versions of the same game.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h1 id="public-archives">Public Archives&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="safety-first">Safety First!&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Always be careful when downloading and especially when executing ANYTHING from public sources!&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>It&amp;rsquo;s hard to check ingenuity of the old or abandoned software so at least scan it with antivirus.&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Make sure you doing it in a safe environment like virtual machine or isolated box.&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Never run anything questionable along side of ANY critical or personal data!&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Respect the intellectual property rights.&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://archive.org/details/software/">The Internet Archive Software Collection&lt;/a>: largest vintage and historical software library in the world, providing instant access to millions of programs, CD-ROM images, documentation and multimedia. The collection includes a broad range of software related materials including shareware, freeware, video news releases about software titles, speed runs of actual software game play, previews and promos for software games, high-score and skill replays of various game genres, and the art of filmmaking with real-time computer game engines.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.patches-scrolls.de">The Patches Scrolls&lt;/a>: a very well known website that hosts patches, mods and demos for games since 1995.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://macintoshgarden.org/">The Macintosh Garden&lt;/a>: is an &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Abandonware">abandonware&lt;/a> archive, dedicated in particular to supporting the Macintosh computer platform. A notable feature of Macintosh Garden is its emphasis on emulation, encouraging users to run historical software on modern systems. Software featured on the Macintosh Garden has been discontinued by their publishers and is no longer commercially available. The Macintosh Garden aims to preserve these treasures for future generations, providing documentation and downloads of the original files.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.myabandonware.com/">My Abandonware&lt;/a>: was created in February 2009. Over the years, thousands of games have been added to the site. Authors want to create the best video game museum on the web and let everyone around the world enjoy the incredible amount of great software created in the 80s and 90s. 18k+ games are available at the moment.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.tosecdev.org/">TOSEC&lt;/a>: The Old School Emulation Center (TOSEC) is a retrocomputing initiative dedicated to the cataloging and preservation of software, firmware and resources for microcomputers, minicomputers and video game consoles. The main goal of the project is to catalog and audit various kinds of software and firmware images for these systems.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Also take a look at:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://circuitshelter.com/posts/free-and-open-source-game-engines">free and open source game engines&lt;/a> that allows to play old games on modern platforms.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></content></item><item><title>RetroArch now available on the Amazon App Store</title><link>https://circuitshelter.com/posts/retroarch-amazon-app-store/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 11:47:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://circuitshelter.com/posts/retroarch-amazon-app-store/</guid><description>As of this moment, RetroArch is available on:
Directly (here) Steam (here, available by requesting access) Google Play Store (here and here) Amazon App Store (here) RetroArch is a frontend for emulators, game engines and media players.
It enables you to run classic games on a wide range of computers and consoles through its slick graphical interface. Settings are also unified so configuration is done once and for all.</description><content>&lt;p>As of this moment, RetroArch is available on:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Directly&lt;/strong> (&lt;a href="https://www.retroarch.com/?page=platforms">here&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Steam&lt;/strong> (&lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1118310/RetroArch/">here&lt;/a>, available by requesting access)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Google Play Store&lt;/strong> (&lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.retroarch">here&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.retroarch.aarch64">here&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Amazon App Store&lt;/strong> (&lt;a href="https://amazon.com/dp/B09753XRVF">here&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.retroarch.com/">RetroArch&lt;/a> is a frontend for emulators, game engines and media players.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It enables you to run classic games on a wide range of computers and consoles through its slick graphical interface. Settings are also unified so configuration is done once and for all.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In addition to this, you are able to run original game discs (CDs) from RetroArch.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>RetroArch has advanced features like shaders, netplay, rewinding, next-frame response times, runahead, machine translation, blind accessibility features, and more!&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>The Legend of Fatslob</title><link>https://circuitshelter.com/posts/the-legend-of-fatslob/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 07:24:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://circuitshelter.com/posts/the-legend-of-fatslob/</guid><description> Also check out:
The Legend of WALL</description><content>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9RfM1NQx-i8" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Also check out:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://circuitshelter.com/posts/the-legend-of-wall">The Legend of WALL&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></content></item><item><title>Fix for screen tearing on linux using NVIDIA drivers</title><link>https://circuitshelter.com/posts/linux-nvidia-drivers-tearing-fix/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2021 08:21:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://circuitshelter.com/posts/linux-nvidia-drivers-tearing-fix/</guid><description>Sometimes when using proprietary NVIDIA drivers on linux machine you can experience something like this. Unfortunately this is a very common issue on laptops with hybrid graphics using NVIDIA Optimus. To address this the trick called PRIME Synchronization was introduced back in 2016, it works well but to be able to use it linux users often need to enable it manually.
Solution Make sure that you using drivers &amp;gt;=364.12
Add nvidia-drm.</description><content>&lt;p>Sometimes when using proprietary NVIDIA drivers on linux machine you can experience &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Screen_tearing">something like this&lt;/a>.
Unfortunately this is a very common issue on laptops with hybrid graphics using &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nvidia_Optimus">NVIDIA Optimus&lt;/a>.
To address this the trick called &lt;a href="https://forums.developer.nvidia.com/t/prime-and-prime-synchronization/">PRIME Synchronization was introduced back in 2016&lt;/a>, it works well but to be able to use it linux users often need to enable it manually.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="solution">Solution&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Make sure that you using drivers &lt;code>&amp;gt;=364.12&lt;/code>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Add &lt;code>nvidia-drm.modeset=1&lt;/code> parameter to &lt;code>GRUB_CMDLINE_LINUX_DEFAULT&lt;/code> line in &lt;code>/etc/default/grub&lt;/code> file.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So it&amp;rsquo;s gonna look like this:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4">&lt;code class="language-c" data-lang="c">GRUB_CMDLINE_LINUX_DEFAULT&lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;quiet splash nvidia-drm.modeset=1&amp;#34;&lt;/span>
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>Update GRUB bootloader:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4">&lt;code class="language-sh" data-lang="sh">update-grub
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>Restart your machine&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="links">Links&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://wiki.archlinux.org/title/Kernel_mode_setting">Arch Wiki: Kernel mode setting&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://wiki.archlinux.org/title/NVIDIA#DRM_kernel_mode_setting">Arch Wiki: NVIDIA DRM kernel mode setting&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></content></item><item><title>The Legend of WALL</title><link>https://circuitshelter.com/posts/the-legend-of-wall/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2021 03:53:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://circuitshelter.com/posts/the-legend-of-wall/</guid><description/><content>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/X5ecZEs2Y0o" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div></content></item><item><title>Widelands 1.0 Released</title><link>https://circuitshelter.com/posts/widelands-1.0/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 05:33:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://circuitshelter.com/posts/widelands-1.0/</guid><description>Widelands is a free, open source real-time strategy game with singleplayer campaigns and a multiplayer mode. The game was inspired by Settlers IIâ„¢ (Â© Bluebyte) but has significantly more variety and depth to it.
Since the release of Build 21, developers implemented several hundreds of new features and bugfixes; for example, to name just a few of the highlights:
A new tribe: the Amazons An add-on system A third frisians scenario Dynamic tribe loading to speed up game loading Targeting individual map objects for removal Mute/unmute messages by buildings Fully redesigned main menu Configurable keyboard shortcuts Enhanced keyboard and mousewheel support in the UI Long-term stable Lua API for game content designers https://www.</description><content>&lt;p>Widelands is a free, open source real-time strategy game with singleplayer campaigns and a multiplayer mode. The game was inspired by Settlers IIâ„¢ (Â© Bluebyte) but has significantly more variety and depth to it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since the release of Build 21, developers implemented several hundreds of new features and bugfixes; for example, to name just a few of the highlights:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>A new tribe: the Amazons
An add-on system
A third frisians scenario
Dynamic tribe loading to speed up game loading
Targeting individual map objects for removal
Mute/unmute messages by buildings
Fully redesigned main menu
Configurable keyboard shortcuts
Enhanced keyboard and mousewheel support in the UI
Long-term stable Lua API for game content designers
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.widelands.org/">https://www.widelands.org/&lt;/a>&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Free and open source game engines</title><link>https://circuitshelter.com/posts/free-and-open-source-game-engines/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 03:48:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://circuitshelter.com/posts/free-and-open-source-game-engines/</guid><description>ðŸ—º Strategy OpenRA: a flexible game engine (the OpenRA engine) that provides a common platform for rebuilding and reimagining classic 2D and 2.5D RTS games. The OpenRA engine is not restricted by the technical limitations of the original games. It includes native support for modern operating systems (like Windows 10, macOS, and Linux) and screen resolutions without relying on emulation or hacks, and integrated online multiplayer.
OpenDUNE: re-creation of the popular game &amp;ldquo;Dune II&amp;rdquo;, originally made by Westwood Studios, and released by Virgin Entertainment.</description><content>&lt;h1 id="-strategy">ðŸ—º Strategy&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.openra.net/">OpenRA&lt;/a>: a flexible game engine (the OpenRA engine) that provides a common platform for rebuilding and reimagining classic 2D and 2.5D RTS games. The OpenRA engine is not restricted by the technical limitations of the original games. It includes native support for modern operating systems (like Windows 10, macOS, and Linux) and screen resolutions without relying on emulation or hacks, and integrated online multiplayer.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenDUNE/OpenDUNE">OpenDUNE&lt;/a>: re-creation of the popular game &amp;ldquo;Dune II&amp;rdquo;, originally made by Westwood Studios, and released by Virgin Entertainment. It attempts to re-create the original game and apply modern technology to it to allow it to be run natively on most operating systems.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://opensage.github.io/">OpenSAGE&lt;/a>: re-implementation of SAGE, the 3D real-time strategy engine used in Command &amp;amp; Conquerâ„¢: Generals and other RTS titles from EA Pacific.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://openage.dev/">openage&lt;/a>: cross-platform RTS game engine that provides the mechanics of Age of Empires.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.openttd.org/">OpenTTD&lt;/a>: simulation game based upon the popular Microprose game &amp;ldquo;Transport Tycoon Deluxe&amp;rdquo;, written by Chris Sawyer. It attempts to mimic the original game as closely as possible while extending it with new features.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://openrct2.org/">OpenRCT2&lt;/a>: re-implementation of RollerCoaster Tycoon 2 (RCT2), expanding the game with new features, fixing bugs and raising game limits.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://corsixth.com/">CorsixTH&lt;/a>: reimplementation of the 1997 Bullfrog business sim Theme Hospital. As well as faithfully recreating the original, CorsixTH adds support for modern operating systems (Windows, macOS, Linux and BSD), high resolutions and much more.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://github.com/bvschaik/julius">Julius&lt;/a>: fully working open-source version of Caesar 3, with the same logic as the original, but with some UI enhancements, that can be played on multiple platforms.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://openfodder.com/">Open Fodder&lt;/a>: is an open source version of the Cannon Fodder, an action-strategy shoot&amp;rsquo;em up game developed by Sensible Software and published by Virgin Interactive.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://ihhub.github.io/fheroes2/">fheroes2&lt;/a>: remake of Heroes of Might and Magic II game engine.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://vcmi.eu/">VCMI&lt;/a>: work-in-progress attempt to recreate engine for Heroes III, giving it new and extended possibilities. Among current features are: complete gameplay mechanics, almost all objects, abilities, basic battle AI and adventure AI.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://openxcom.org/">OpenXcom&lt;/a>: clone of the popular &amp;ldquo;UFO: Enemy Unknown&amp;rdquo; (&amp;ldquo;X-COM: UFO Defense&amp;rdquo; in the USA release) and &amp;ldquo;X-COM: Terror From the Deep&amp;rdquo; videogames by Microprose, licensed under the GPL and written in C++ / SDL.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.siedler25.org/">Return to the Roots&lt;/a>: remake of the original The Settlers 2 which aims to introduce new features such as a multiplayer mode via internet as well as the support for modern hardware and several operating systems.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://github.com/tonihele/OpenKeeper">OpenKeeper&lt;/a>: project goal is to fully implement the game (version 1.7 with 3 bonus packs) as open source cross platform version, with minimal or no changes at all, using the original game assets.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://freesynd.sourceforge.io/">FreeSynd&lt;/a>: is a cross-platform, GPLed reimplementation of engine for the classic Bullfrog game, Syndicate.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h1 id="-rpg">ðŸ“œ RPG&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://freeablo.org/">freeablo&lt;/a>: modern cross platform reimplementation of the game engine used in Diablo 1.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://opendiablo2.com/">OpenDiablo2&lt;/a>: an ARPG game engine in the same vein of the 2000&amp;rsquo;s games, and supports playing Diablo 2. The engine is written in golang and is cross platform.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://openmw.org/">OpenMW&lt;/a>: modern engine which re-implements and extends the 2002 Gamebryo engine for the open-world role-playing game The Elder Scrolls III: Morrowind.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://xoreos.org/">xoreos&lt;/a>: ongoing FLOSS project to reimplement BioWareâ€™s Aurora engine (and derivatives) as used in their 3D games, beginning with Neverwinter Nights. The goal is to have a portable program to play those games even on operating systems those games were never meant to be played on, such as GNU/Linux and Mac OS X.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://gemrb.org/">GemRB&lt;/a>: the goal of the project is to make the Infinity Engine games like Baldur&amp;rsquo;s Gate and Icewind Dale available on a wide range of platforms forever, fix or avoid old bugs, add new features and provide a superb platform for mod development. All done in the open by players for players.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.scummvm.org/">ScummVM&lt;/a>: a set of game engine recreations originally designed to play LucasArts adventure games that use the SCUMM system, it also supports a variety of non-SCUMM games by companies like Revolution Software and Adventure Soft.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://easyrpg.org/">EasyRPG&lt;/a>: community project to create a free, open source, role playing game creation tool, compatible with RPG Maker 2000/2003 games.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h1 id="-fps">ðŸ”« FPS&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.zdoom.org/">ZDoom&lt;/a>: is a family of enhanced ports of the Doom engine for running on modern operating systems. It runs on Windows, Linux, and OS X, and adds new features not found in the games as originally published by id Software.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.eduke32.com/">EDuke32&lt;/a>: free homebrew game engine and source port of the classic PC first person shooter Duke Nukem 3Dâ€” Duke3D for shortâ€”to Windows, Linux, Mac OS X, FreeBSD, several handhelds, your family toaster, and to your girlfriend&amp;rsquo;s vibrator.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://ioquake3.org/">ioquake3&lt;/a>: the intent of this project is to provide a baseline Quake 3 which may be used for further development and baseq3 fun.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.etlegacy.com/">ET: Legacy&lt;/a>: project that aims to create a fully compatible client and server for the popular online FPS game Wolfenstein: Enemy Territory - whose gameplay is still considered unmatched by many, despite its great age.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://github.com/Interrupt/systemshock">Shockolate&lt;/a>: cross platform source port of System Shock, using SDL2. This runs well on OSX, Linux, and Windows.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h1 id="-racing">ðŸŽ Racing&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://opennfs.com/">OpenNFS&lt;/a>: an attempt to recreate the classic Need for Speed Games (1-6), unpacking their original data files into a modern scratch built engine.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></content></item></channel></rss>